Empresses in the Palace—the Legend of Zhen Huan
Adopted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
[contact translators] carsenwei@yahoo.com
[subtitles subscription] liberapay.com/ZHZSubbers
Theme: Unfortunate Love
Perturbed by the thoughts on my mind
no matter how hard I try to sever my love.
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For the lovers of all time,
who can break the spell of romance?
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For the lovers of all time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
[contact translators] carsenwei@yahoo.com
[subtitles subscription] liberapay.com/ZHZSubbers
His majesty are arriving!
All rise.
I am grateful to Your Majesty.
What happened?
I've heard that someone defied the edict, so I come to investigate thoroughly.
Peace to your majesty.
What are you doing here?
I chatted with her highness in the room just now.
Grace and peace to Your Highness.
Why are you here?
Otherwise, where should I be?
I just stayed with Her Highness.
My Lady, How difficult to find you! It is Her Highness's palace that you go.
I have already sent the things here which you want to give Companion Shen.
I just heard some loud noise in the hall of Concubine Estime, so I thought that some great events happened.
Why do you come here instead of staying at the Cooling Hall?
I have heard that someone trespass into the Leisured Moon Chamber to visit the grounded concubine, so I come here to check.
Do you have warrant from the Empress?
I was too anxious to get the warrant from the Empress.
When I grounded Shen, I said that no one could visit her without my permission.
Do you forget?
I...
Then what did you see in the Leisured Moon Chamber?
The head maid Orchid didn't let me in, so I haven't seen Shen yet.
Very good!
You are worthy of serving me directly.
I always abide by Your Majesty’s command.
Your majesty, Her highness always act decisively, she must have some evidence.
What about letting Her Highness into the Leisured Moon Chamber and check it out?
On the one hand, Her Highness don't come here in vain; on the other hand, we could also make it clear.
What do you think, Your Majesty?
Companion Shen is grounded, I can't bear to let her carry the charge of defying the edict.
Your majesty, please let someone get into Leisured Moon Chamber to check in order to prove Companion Shen's innocence.
Although Companion Shen is grounded, we can't wrongly blame her.
Su Peisheng.
I'm here.
Take a few people inside.
Ok.
Your Lordship, these small boats are the only means of transportation on the lake. I'll take you to the island.
Why are there so many lotus lanterns on the lake?
Yesterday was the Ghost Festival, people in the harem put the lanterns to pray for blessing.
How could the lotus lantern compare with the real lotus.
At this time of the year, the true lotuses almost fade.
So I want to see the unwithered lotuses.
Eh...
You all go back first, I'll row myself over.
My Lordship, if His Majesty knew, he would blame us for not taking good care of you.
His Majesty are familiar with my character.
It doesn't matter. Just go back to work.
A-Jin, you go back, too.
Your Majesty
Other than Lady Vertu and a few servants
there is no one else
I was truly concerned upon hearing this fabricated news
I realize I am mistaken
Please forgive me Your Majesty
I'm aware
there are nonstop gossips and fights within the harem
As the head of Palace Affairs
you should be able to tell what's wrong from what's right
I have not done my duty well. Please forgive me Your Majesty
I thought you have changed after the self-reflection
but instead it made your temper even worse
Originally I was planning to give back your position as the head of Palace Affairs
but it seems that there is no more need
Go back to your own palace and reflect
stop causing so much drama
Thank you for your kindness Your Majesty
You are no longer allowed to see Princess WenYi
lest you set a bad exmaple for her
Your Majesty. I have one more thing to say.
Go ahead
I was pondering
Lady Vertu has been on good behavior during this lengthy house arrest
Can Your Majesty remove half of the guards?
On one hand, we no longer need to waste the guards.
On the other hand, with so many royal Ladies coming and going
the guards are more or less an inconvenience
making people somewhat restless.
I concur
Please take care of her as she is in your palace
I will gladly accept your wish. I will take my leave now.
I'm glad you were not implicated
I will not put myself in a bad situation
I also do not want to disobey Your Majesty's orders
His Majesty is leaving
I bid Your Majesty goodbye
I was too careless and fell into your trap!
Carelessness or not, only Your Majesty would know.
Today you won
I regret not crushing you earlier
Your Majesty must be joking
We all serve the Emperor as part of the same harem
If the Emperor gets a wind of this
His Majesty would be mad again
You are happy since the Emperor is favoring you at the moment
As long as I'm around
I will not tolerate scheming people like you
Whether if I can be tolerated is up to Your Highness;
whether if I can please Your Highness all depends on me.
We have a long way to go
Let's see who's smiles at the end
Leave
By His Majesty's decree
The palace will only need to staff half of the gurads
You bunch can go back now
Yes
Lady Sourire gave you these rewards as a token of appreciation
What about us?
Not too worry
Her Highness Estime appreciates your hard work
She has prepared tea and snacks for you
Many thanks to Lady Estime
However we are on duty right now
We cannot be eating
No problem
All your hard work here in the palace
has not gone unnoticed by Her Highness Estime
As long as you guys perform your duties favorably
Lady Estime will speak fondly of you all in front of the Emperor
Thanks Madam
We won't hold back then
Alright, let's go.
Okay
There will be more rewards afterwards
My Lady, your speculation is confirmed.
Jade sneaked out from the back door to Noble Lady Cao's palace,
a short while after you lady and Vermilion's leave.
My Lady,
I could detain her if you like.
I rather like you to act as if nothing has happened.
Yes, My Lady.
You should go now.
I shall question her in person.
Yes.
I have hidden the boat deep in the lotus clumps.
You Lady won't be noticed on the way back.
Allow me to take my leave.
I shall get changed.
Bitch!
Deceive me together with Zhen Huan!
Your Highness, please compose yourself for your health's sake.
Obviously, they have schemed on the false surrender,
deceiving me into believing in her entirely.
It is.
I should have kept my eyes wide open,
rather than was blinded to the truth.
by Jade's pitiful but spurious look.
Well, you always act in practical prudence.
It's fairly uncommon for you
to bring me the message in such a rush.
I only cared too much on Your Highness's annoyance.
Noble Lady Sourire's disrespect towards Your Highness
indicates a future threat if we couldn't exterminate her in time.
Your care on it is valuable indeed.
Your Highness,
may peace restore in your mind, in the smell of the pleasancy.
His Majesty's temper comes completely
from his exceeding concern on you.
I rather worry that His Majesty would put aside my sorrow
when he is absorbed by the joy from the new concubines.
Madam
This is the time for the guards to shift duties.
Half of the former guards left by order moments ago.
The last half guard the palace idly.
Some knockout drops have been added into their food.
Now they must feel drowsy.
The door has been half-opened.
I may walk You Lady indoors.
You may go. Be unnoticed.
Avoid catching others' attention.
Yes.
Meizhuang.
Your hands are as cold as ice.
Don't worry for me. I' m good.
Madam Orchid kept reassuring me that you are in good conditions.
I treated her words with doubt.
Seeing you here, my doubt has been dispelled.
Nothing has been wrong with me.
But I can't help concerning on your condition.
You Ladies, I would stay outside and watch the guards.
Time is limited. The guards may resume their duties soon.
This is no longer the sumptuous Leisured Moon Chamber any more.
But you remains a position in the concubines.
These... these brazen service men dare to skimp on you.
Consort Fleur is in her prime.
No wonder that in this harem
service men yearn to flatter her
through the disdain on me.
If Madam Orchid hadn't offered help secretly,
I could hardly survive the torture they imposed on me.
Farrah
I have told our families to hunt Liu Ben down.
His Majesty will surely compensate you and declare you innocnet when the truth comes out.
He cannot compensate my suffering during these days at all.
I was the center of his attention but then he abandoned, and distrusted me.
His Majesty, is truly fickle,
totally ignoring the affection in the bygone days.
I know, that it is harsh for you to hear this words.
But only when I am in the plight did I finally understand
that His Majesty's affection is just it .
Nevertheless, you will not be like me as His Majesty treats you extremely well.
These words are just heartbroken words from a heartbroken person.
knock sound
My Lady please come out right away otherwise you will be found out.
Mei
Be sure to take care of your health.
I will definitely do whatever I can to save you out of here.
My Lady, please come out as fast as you can.
My Lady please come out quickly.
Be sure to take care.
Go.
Auntie, please take care of her. Please assist her for anything.
My Lady, please be assured. The situation more or less will calm down after today's farce. Her Lady Mei's days will be better.
My Lady please go back to your chamber.
Who is there ?
Who is on the boat ?
Who is it ?
Who is it that interrupting my beautiful dream?
I don't know Your Lordship is here. Please forgive me for having interrupted Your Lordship
Leave. Don't disturb my good mood.
May I know why Your Lordship is here?
His Majesty asked me to stay the night in the palace. Do you even need to ask ?
Yes. Yes.
It's fine now.
How about I escort you back by rowing this boat
as it would be faster and more convenient.
Thank you, Your Lordship.
What I’ve already known is that,
the lake is full of lotus in bloom and the wind brings fragrance from far away.
Now surrendered by the blossom,
I can even feel the delicate smell of trapa’s leaves and reeds.
Sure enough, one can enjoy more just in the beauty rather than far away.
Now seed pods are quite hard to find.
How can Your Lordship collect so many lotuses?
This is the last bouquet in this summer.
I rafted into the deep blossom only collected this amount.
Do Your Lordship like lotus?
It seems men usually prefer pine and bamboo.
Pine and bamboo are hard, but likely to be fractured.
On the contract, growing out of mud, the lotus blooms untainted.
While the purity of lotus is widely complimented,
I prefer its Buddhism nature.
Mild like a loving mother.
Yes, I agree.
Is there a smell of Pollia?
But it shouldn’t be in this season.
Sensitive sense, Lady. It belongs to me.
Pollia stands for love.
Do Your Lordship have someone beloved?
It is a real enjoyment boating with a beauty today,
which resembles the story of boating on the Lake Tai with Xishi.
I would be angry,
if I didn’t know what Your Lordship really wanted to express.
Could Your Lordship please not compare me with Xishi?
Why? Do you also regard Xishi as Helen of Troy,
just like the vulgar ones?
If Xishi is accused of breaking down Kingdom Wu,
who should be the culprit for the collapse of Yue?
Lady Sourire is always courteous. Why did you say that?
Fanli, Xishi’s lover
was exactly the person who sent Xishi to Kingdom Wu as a concubine.
What a fickle man.
Later Xishi disregarded previous enmity and went boating with Fanli on the Lake Tai.
However, I believe the pure affectionateness at first sight must have disappeared.
People either pour sympathy on Xishi, or blame King of Wu.
But Fanli is out of blame.
I’m ashamed of my inferiority in front of your special idea.
The moonlight pours down like silver.
Wonderful moment and beautiful scene are really precious.
In spite of wonderful moment and beautiful scene, I’ve no mood to enjoy it.
Have Your Lordship also read the Peony Pavilion?
I love this sentence most:
Love once begins, will never ends.
It contains the power to kill, but also to revive.
Love, is only one word.
One who wants to seek its source, may be perplexed in chasing.
Love always begins nowhere and ends nowhere.
It’s a fortune for Your Lordship to find a beloved one.
I accompany His Majesty from dawn to dusk.
How I wish we could have this kind of love.
You had dropped something your Lordship
Thanks
This sachet is my preciousness
It will be a great regret if I lost it
Just a sachet
You’ve made it so seriously
Since it is your Lordship's preciousness
Then don’t show it to others
Which may be troublesome
May I pardon you with a thing
Please talk freely
The night at QiXi's banquet
I was once plunged into a trouble
But fortunately saved by Consort Honnête
So no matter what your Lordship heard about that night
Don’t ever mention our encounter
So as tonight
I will be more that grateful if your Lordship agree with it
I won’t tell anyone else
It is such a honor to speak glowingly with you my Lady
If your are available one day
I would invite you to the Cooling Hall
To talk about ancient and modern times
Summer has just past
It too cool for the Cooling Hall
I shall not come to bother
Goodbye
You eventually arrived back my Lady
Pour me some water Jade
Everything went smoothly my Lady?
I worried about you since you haven’t came back at such a late night
What are you worrying about
Your safety my Lady
I was just fine but Consort Fleur was not
The emperor scolded her
And forbade her from seeing Princess WenYi
The emperor was considering to resume her
the authority in assistance in palace affairs
Now it seems that she couldn’t even save herself
The emperor scolded Consort Fleur
Yes
She had to blame herself for the penny wise pound foolish action
Harming won’t bring one's good
Am I right Jade
What you have said is undoubtedly right
You have been labored and toiled with mind and body these days Jade
I admire your hard work
Why did you say that my Lady, I can’t bear it
Lady Cao stirring up with the fact that emperor pretended to be Lord XVII to meet me
At that time I suspected that it was someone close to me
Who let out the secret
Today the instant I stepped out Bitong Shuyuan
Someone went out to send a secret message
I couldn’t believe that
Consort Fleur knew it already
I was going to the Leisured Moon Chamber
I am not the only person to know
My Lady went to Lady Meizhuang's.
Why My Lady thinks it was me(who leaked out the secret)?
Definitely you are prudent.
But one thing was neglected.
What?
The tributary Mi He spice.
His Majesty gave it all to me.
And I in turn gave it all to Lady Cao.
I myself saw her putting it in the inner chamber.
If you didn't have disroyalty as you said.
How could you go to her inner chamber?
How could the odour of Mi He Spice linger on your clothes?
I...I didn't.
If you don't admit,
you can smell your clothes
to see whether the fragrance exits.
It takes days for the odour to subside(fade/vanish)
once it adhere to your clothes.
Besides, the fragrance is too faint to be noticed.
Will you still tell the lie?
My Lady.
But I want to thank you anyway.
Were it not for the fact that you tipped Consort Fleur off
I wouldn't topple Consort Fleur today readily.
I am afraid that Consort Fleur detest you now,
considering it a good play co-directed by us.
It is not uncommon to see traitorous maids.
I just never thought that the person who impaired me
is my sister
You have known that.
Yes, I have known it.
My father had told me before I came to the palace.
It is because I know you are my sister
that my heart hurts
Father...what did father say?
He said he had chargrined you for years
and let me treat you well.
That is why I took you to the palace with me.
Find a decent family for you.
You marry him as his legal wife.
If you stay at home,
you will marry a manservant at most.
Your marriage will be your lifelong encumberance.
My Lady.
Do you still call me My Lady?
You should call me sister.
I know you are not reconciled at all.
Although you are father's daughter,
there isn't your name in the pedigree.
You cannot be named with the word generation Yu, either.
Even your mother's memorial tablet
cannot be worshiped in the ancestral hall.
But Jade, father has you in his heart.
I, as your older sister, have you in my heart.
No matter how well you treat me,
in this agonistic imperial harem,
if no one can recommend me,
I will never see the daylight.
Do you believe Lady Cao will recommend you?
Concubine Beauté and Escort Yu are good examples of miserable cat's paw.
At the very least,
even if you are endowed with favor,
it won't last permanently.
Once the reality is enclosed that your mother's father is the former convict.
Do you know what will happen?
Not only the Zhen family will be implicated
but our father will be banished to the Tower Ninggu as well
for the accusation of marrying a convict's daughter.
I didn't intend to impair you and our father.
I didn't mean to compare with you, either.
Lady Cao said His Majesty liked you exclusively.
Even if he knew you had made mistakes,
he won't castigate you.
Penting you up for ten days is the most.
As for me, I will stand a chance to access His Majesty
because my face resembles yours a little bit
How could you be credulous od her nonsense?
I have already lived in their menace
despite I did nothing wrong.
If His Majesty is really irritated by me,
your face will only entail his aversion.
You could only escape death by sheer luck.
I was indeed possessed by the devil at that time.
Your miscalculation at that moment almost breaks our relationship apart.
Do you know that I'm also envious of you in some ways?
Unlike you, my fate is destined.
I can't escape it.
But you still have the chance to spend the rest of your life with someone you genuinely love.
In the palace, although I can't treat you like a sister,
I will make you the adoptive daughter of our father and be married from the family of Zhen.
Your mother's memorial tablet could be placed in the ancestral hall of Zhen.
And your named could be written in the family tree.
Then your wish could be realized.
Old sister, I'm insane.
Had I known your attentiveness to me, I wouldn't have make such a big mistake.
Yurao is still young and there's no boy in our family.
She could rely on nobody but us.
If discord is sowed between us by the evil
and lose our trust,
there's no hope for our family's glory.
I didn't live up to you, please forgive me.
You didn't tell Consort Fleur about your mother, did you?
I only wanted to use Consort Fleur and Lady Cao to draw His Majesty's attention.
I didn't mean to do harm to you.
My mother's identity is very important.
I didn't dare to tell them.
It's very lucky that you didn't.
Consort Fleur and her followers will definitely bear malice to you since today.
You have to be more than careful in days to come.
I have already made a mistake.
I'm more than regretful.
Please trust me this time.
It's getting cold early here, and mosquitos are dying out.
The day we return to the palace will be the Mid-Autumn Festival.
My Lady.......
What are you worrying about?
I find that His Majesty really respects Concubine Jing.
Concubine Jing earns her respect for her grace and obedience.
His Majesty doesn't favor her but treats her with respect.
In the palace, many people have hidden their light under a bushel.
If she really has no light, how could she have lived undisturbed for so long under Consort Fleur?
I think there's something wrong with Lady Cao in this incident.
Think about it.
Although Consort Fleur is impetuous, Lady Cao is cautious indeed.
Even if you purposely sent Jade to report, how could Lady Cao didn't remind her to think twice?
Is that because she did it purposely or she totally believed in what Jade has said?
Could it be that she connived at Consort Fleur's going?
If Cao Qinmo didn't poison Princess Winyi, it must be Consort Fleur.
Cao Qinmo has only one daughter she loves, so there's space between them.
I think it's possible.
Mm.
If it's true, then this round is far more complicated.
Please put more honey, in case it's too sour.
I heard from Xiao-Xiazi that
Noble Prince Guo recently
seldom comes into palace for chess and paintings,
but travels in Shu.
What does it matter to us?
A Noble Prince could go wherever he wants to go.
Unlike us, the square-shaped sky is all we can see
when we look up.
Look how whiny you are!
You'd be free enough when you get married one day.
Since marriage is all you talk about,
it must be your wish!
Stop saying that!
Be careful of your mouth!
Amitabha! Look at you!
Since you care so much whether Noble Prince Guo come into palace,
What about you marrying him?
Such crazy words!
I will ignore you if you continue this nonsense.
Oh! My kind sister!
I'm just kidding.
Anyway, I will wait for your gratitude
when my prediction comes true one day.
Stop that nonsense!
Stop!
What's wrong? Look at you!
Just stop that nonsense!
Your majesty, the Empress is bathing and dressing.
You may sleep if you feel tired.
I am reading Sushi's poems.
Ten years, dead and living dim and draw apart.
I don't try to remember, But forgetting is hard.
What an excellent poem! Every word goes in my deep mind.
Your majesty, I can hardly understand it.
Neither does the Empress, maybe.
If only Lady Sourire is here and talk with me.
Here's one thing I need you to send to the Palace of Pearl Jade.
Yes, your majesty.
My lady, here's Mr.Su.
My lady, may you forgive my disturbing.
Is there something happening since you come at this late time?
Here's one thing that the Emperor asked me to definitely give you.
And wish my lady a good dream in this beautiful night.
The belts fastened in my waist, would like to tangle together like our hearts.
Is it written by the Emperor himself?
Yes, it is.
Please convey my gratitude to the Emperor, Mr.Su.
The Emperor is so tired of national affairs.
Where is Su Peisheng?
I just saw that Mr.Su going to the Palace of Pearl Jade
with a box in his hands.
What's in the box?
It's a true lover's knot.
May you not be angry, your majesty.
Is there any reason for me to get angry?
Since the Emperor came back to palace,
did he ever visit Consort Fleur?
They usually meet in daily life.
But the Emperor didn't call Consort Fleur to serve him.
Hello
[contact translators] carsenwei@yahoo.com
[subtitles subscription] liberapay.com/ZHZSubbers
Theme: The Lonely Phoenix
[phoenix is the symbol of an empress]
I dimly recall the colorful blooms in every summer.
They are as distant as the autumn moon in the water.
He loved me with a volatile heart.
And before I knew it, we fell apart.
Behind me are the promises and longing.
Before me lie the flute and the zither.
I loved you with my body and soul
But you hurt me from head to toe.
My wish ran athwart
and I ended up a fool of my destiny.
My love was the wind-swept flowers from a tree.
A plum bloomed in winter hoping for a fruitful summer.
But the irresistible winds of destiny destroyed her wish.
You can hear the flapping of a phoenix
but you will never see it.
What you see is the falling leaves from the phoenix tree.
The falling leaves from the phoenix tree.